JUAN IGNACIO **NAVARRETE**

56 9 7709 5128 · linkedin.com/in/juan-ignacio-navarrete-bañados-b21468b5 **ji.navarreteb91@gmail.com** ·

·Portfolio:https://jinavarrete.github.io/JuanlgnacioNavarreteDataAnalyst.github.io/

I am a Data Engineer with over two years of experience, specialize in AWS Cloud, ETL processes in Python, Spark, and Pentaho. As a Data Analyst, I have extensive experience with SQL databases and BI data architecture. I am also skilled in Data Visualization using Power BI (*Microsoft DA-100*), QuickSight, and Tableau.

SKILLS

- Data Visualization: Power BI (Expert) Tableau (Intermediate) – QuickSight (Expert)
- **DB/DW**: SQL (Advanced) RedShift (Proficient).
- Big Data: Spark (Proficient) Hadoop (Intermediate)
- ETL: Python (Proficient) Pentaho (Proficient), AWS Glue (Proficient)
- Cloud: AWS (Proficient) GCP (Beginner) Azure (Beginner).
- Others: Dockers (Proficient) Lynux (Intermediate).

EXPERIENCE

2022/03 - PRESENT

BI DEVELOPER, GLOBAL 66

- AWS Data Pipelining: Designed and managed robust data pipelines on AWS for Data Warehouse creation.
- RedShift Expertise: Crafted scalable Data Warehouses in RedShift, ensuring data efficiency and security.
- Reporting Migration: Spearheaded the organization-wide reporting transition from QuickSight to Tableau, enhancing data visualization.
- Automated Regulatory Reporting: Developed automated reports with AWS Lambda and Glue Jobs, supporting business units and ensuring regulatory compliance.
- Daily Reconciliations: Automated daily file processes, streamlining reconciliations.
- Dashboard Development: Built insightful dashboards for business units using QuickSight and Tableau, driving data-informed decisions.

2021/09 - 2022/03

BUSINESS ANALYST, GLOBAL 66

- Creation of dashboards and reports in QuickSight and SalesForces for the measurement of internal KPI's of the Compliance area.
- Modeling of the main processes of the area for their documentation and re-engineering.

2019/09 - 2021/10

DATA ANALYST, APPARTNER

Responsible for the preparation of ETL's processes, design and creation of BI architecture
for Data Marts. In charge of designing prototypes and creating reports with the Power BI
tool for clients in the shipping and insurance industries.

- Weekly contact with clients to review requirements in process and pending, and the survey of new requirements or improvement options.
- Maintenance improvements in reports already created in Power BI.

D2020/07 - 2020/11

BI CONSULTANT, KRO SOLUTIONS

- Responsible for the design of prototypes for Operational and Management Control reports. Construction of reports with the Power BI tool.
- In charge of the visual proposal of the design of the reports.

2019/10 - 2020/06

MACROS EXCEL CONSULTANT, IANDES GESTORA INMOBILIARIA

Creation of automated Excel spreadsheet for evaluation of real estate projects.

2020/01 - 2020/06

PROCESS ANALYST, DEV-MENTOR

• Requirements analysis and documentation of processes for consultancy on the technological Roadmap of a company in the Factoring industry. Participation in analysis and design of a proposal on technological Roadmap.

2017/05 - 2018/12

PROJECT MANAGER, DEV-MENTOR

- Leader in several projects of survey of requirements in different levels of depth.
- Responsible for the service of a dedicated help desk for industry clients.

2016/05 - 2017/04

SERVICE MANAGER, SONDA S.A.

 Responsible for operational continuity of IT services. Monitoring of service quality. Cost tracking. Follow-up of Incidents and urgent requirements. Propose Improvement Opportunities.

EDUCATION

2016/01

INDUSTRIAL CIVIL ENGINEERING, UNIVERSIDAD TÉCNICA FEDERICO SANTA MARÍA

Title work: Empirical study on the relationship between religion and the economy.

2022/05

GRADUATED IN MANAGEMENT ANALYTICS, PONTIFÍCIA UNIVERSIDAD CATÓLICA DE CHILE

LANGUAGES

- **Spanhis**: Native speaker.
- **Portugués**: Advanced level (oral and written)
- English: Upper Intermediate TOEFL Certificate: B2+ level CEFR (Common European Framework